Guide to the Investigation Files of the Rapp-Coudert Committee TAM.533
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Microfilm Reel List (with Cross-Reference to Original Box and Folder Locations), 1919-1953
  - Young Communist League Brooklyn College Chapter: Includes Photocopies of Newspapers, Periodicals and Flyers, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 21-0187, Box-folder 8-RC376)
  - Young Communist League City College Chapter: Includes Photocopies of Newspapers, Periodicals, and Flyers, 1935-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 21-0321, Box-folder 8-RC377)
  - Young Communist League Hunter College Chapter: Includes Flyers, Apr 1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 21-0543, Box-folder 8-RC378)
  - Zeller, Belle (Head of Government Department, Brooklyn College), 1940-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 21-0554, Box-folder 8-RC379)
  - "Summary of Evidence Secured against Individuals now in Educational Systems" (List of 684 individuals) Copy of RC-560,2, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 21-0565, Box-folder 8-RC380)
  - Teachers Union Local 5: Includes Newspapers and Periodicals, Statement of Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) at Open Hearing of Rapp-Coudert Committee, 1935-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 21-0729, Box-folder 8-RC381)
  - Teachers Union-Executive Committee Minutes: Includes Memoranda and Correspondence between Local 5 and the American Federation of Teachers, 1932-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 22-0001, Box-folder 9-RC382,1)
  - Teachers Union-Executive Committee Minutes, 1936-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 22-0251, Box-folder 9-RC382,2)
  - Teachers Union Chapter Minutes: Includes New York University, Brooklyn College, Sarah Lawrence, and Columbia Chapters' Minutes and Correspondence, 1934-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 22-0428, Box-folder 9-RC383)
  - College Teachers Union: Includes "The Conspiracy Against the Schools: An Analysis of Rapp Coudert March 1940 to January 1941", Flyers and Correspondence, 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 22-0520, Box-folder 9-RC384)
  - Teachers Union General: Includes Photostats of Newspapers and Periodicals, Memoranda, 1933-1940, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 22-0787, Box-folder 9-RC385)
  - List of Active Members of Teachers Union as of Oct 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0001, Box-folder 9-RC386,1)
  - List of Active Members of Teachers Union as of Oct 1940: Photo Positive (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0097, Box-folder 9-RC386,2)
  - List of Active Members of Teachers Union as of Oct 1940: Photo Negative (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0223, Box-folder 9-RC386,3)
  - Former Members of Teachers Union as of Oct 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0323, Box-folder 9-RC387)
  - General Membership Meeting of New York College Chapter Teachers Union: Includes Minutes and Bulletins, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0435, Box-folder 9-RC388)
  - Executive Council Minutes of New York College Chapter Teachers Union, 1938-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0511, Box-folder 9-RC389)
  - Executive Council Minutes of New York College Chapter Teachers Union, Jan 1938-Dec 1938 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0559, Box-folder 9-RC390)
  - Executive Council Minutes of New York College Chapter Teachers Union, Jan 1939-Dec 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0612, Box-folder 9-RC391)
  - Executive Council Minutes of New York College Chapter Teachers Union, Jan 1940-Dec 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0675, Box-folder 9-RC392)
  - Executive Council Minutes of New York College Chapter Teachers Union, Jan 1941-Apr 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0752, Box-folder 9-RC393)
  - Committee Minutes and Memoranda of New York College Chapter Teachers Union: Includes Committee of Non-Instructional Staff, Educational Policies Committee, Executive Board, 1937-1940, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 23-0775, Box-folder 9-RC394)
  - Opposition File: Includes Clippings and Publications on Opposition to Communism in the Teachers Union, 1938-1942, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 24-0001, Box-folder 9-RC395)
  - Teachers Union Minutes, Legal Aid Grievances, Academic Freedom Committee: Includes Memoranda, Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings on the Blumberg, Begun, and Burroughs Case, 1932-1937, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 24-0158, Box-folder 9-RC396,1)
  - Teachers Union Minutes: Includes Minutes of Delegate Assembly, Membership Meeting, and General Meeting, 1933-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 24-0433, Box-folder 9-RC396,2)
  - Hendley, Charles J. Correspondence (President, Teachers Union): Includes Correspondence between Hendley and the Board of Education, 1938-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 24-0619, Box-folder 10-RC397,1)
  - Hendley, Charles J. Correspondence (President, Teachers Union): Includes Correspondence between Hendley and the Board of Education, 1935-1938, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 24-0825, Box-folder 10-RC397,2)
  - Local 5 College Section of Teachers Union Miscellaneous Records: Includes Correspondence of Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union), Newspaper Clippings, and Flyers, 1936-1937, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0001, Box-folder 10-RC398)
  - Brooklyn Elementary Schools: List of Active Members of the Teachers Union in Brooklyn Elementary Schools, Sep 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0196, Box-folder 10-RC399)
  - High Schools: List of Active Members of the Teachers Union in High Schools, Sep 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0313, Box-folder 10-RC400)
  - Evening Schools: List of Active Members of the Teachers Union in Evening Schools, Sep 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0475, Box-folder 10-RC401)
  - Manhattan Elementary Schools: List of Active Members of the Teachers Union in Manhattan Elementary Schools, Sep 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0489, Box-folder 10-RC402)
  - Elementary Schools: Queens and Richmond - List of Active Members of the Teachers Union in Queens and Richmond Elementary Schools, Sep 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0558, Box-folder 10-RC403)
  - Bronx Elementary Schools: List of Active Members of the Teachers Union in Bronx Elementary Schools, Sep 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0580, Box-folder 10-RC404)
  - Private Schools: List of Active Members of the Teachers Union in Private Schools, Sep 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0647, Box-folder 10-RC405)
  - Special Documents - Teachers Union: Includes Photocopies of Daily Worker and The Communist, 1936-1938, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0679, Box-folder 10-RC406)
  - Teachers Union: Includes Rapp-Coudert Reports on Teachers Union Meetings, Teachers Union Publications, Correspondence between Teachers Union and Board of Education, 1938-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0702, Box-folder 10-RC407)
  - Teachers Union Correspondence to Superintendent of Schools: Mostly Correspondence between Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) and Harold Campbell (Superintendent of Schools), Jan 1940-Aug 1940, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 25-0894, Box-folder 10-RC408)
  - Teachers Union Correspondence to Superintendent of Schools: Mostly Correspondence between Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) and Harold Campbell (Superintendent of Schools), Jan 1938-Dec 1938, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 26-0001, Box-folder 10-RC409)
  - Teacher Worker Private Exhibit, May 1937 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 26-0365, Box-folder 10-RC410)
  - Teachers Union Propaganda Against United States (the Committee): Includes the Board of Higher Education Majority Report Trial Committee vs. Philip Foner, "An Analysis of the New York Teacher", Rapp Coudert Report on Teachers Union Meeting, Newspapers and Periodicals, 1933-1942, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 26-0371, Box-folder 10-RC411)
  - Material from Smallhuaser Regarding Teachers Union Elections: Includes Teachers Union Flyers, Memoranda, Correspondence, and Publications, 1934-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 26-0646, Box-folder 10-RC412)
  - New York Teacher News, 1943-1944 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 26-0694, Box-folder 10-RC413)
  - Miscellaneous: Includes Articles, Flyers, and Publications, 1931-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 26-0710, Box-folder 10-RC414)
  - College Newsletter, Publication of the New York College Teachers Union Local 537 American Federation of Teachers, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 26-0749, Box-folder 10-RC415)
  - Miscellaneous: Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews (mostly with voluntary informants), Memoranda, Flyers and Clippings, 1940-1943, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 27-0001, Box-folder 10-RC416)
  - New York Teacher, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 27-0159, Box-folder 10-RC417)
  - Booklets on Communism: Includes Workers of the World, Unite, The Communist, School for Democracy Course Listings, and Others, 1940-1944 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 27-0444, Box-folder 10-RC417a)
  - Arbib-Costa, Alfonso (Professor of Romance Languages, CCNY), 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 27-0658, Box-folder 10-RC418)
  - Bortolaia, Carlo: Includes Photostats of Imperio and Italian American Commercial Review, 1936-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 27-0686, Box-folder 10-RC419)
  - Califano, Augustus (McKee Vocational High School, Staten Island), May 1940, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0001, Box-folder 11-RC420)
  - Casa Italiana Educational Bureau (Columbia University), 1935 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0008, Box-folder 11-RC421)
  - F.P. Castorina and the Gabriel D'Annunzio Circolo, Oct 1938 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0014, Box-folder 11-RC422)
  - Ceroni, Vittorio F. (Professor of Italian, Hunter College): Includes Roma Immortalis, Roma Universalis, 1930-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0020, Box-folder 11-RC423)
  - Colla, Clara (Italian Teacher, Morris High School, Bronx), Mar 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0096, Box-folder 11-RC424)
  - Covello, Leonard (Chairman of Italian Department at Dewitt Clinton High School), Associated with Casa Italiana (RC421), 1935, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0099, Box-folder 11-RC425)
  - Criscuolo, Luigi (Editor of The Rubicon and publicist for A. Hollander and Sons Newark fur dyeing firm), Jul 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0115, Box-folder 11-RC426)
  - D'Annunzio Material (Ugo V.), Italian Library of Information: Includes Rapp-Coudert Committee Requests for Mailing Lists and Publications, Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0122, Box-folder 11-RC427)
  - Della Chiesa, Carolyn (Teacher Abraham Lincoln High School): Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews with Teachers and Staff at Abraham Lincoln High School, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0191, Box-folder 11-RC428)
  - Fenlon, Edward I. (Professor of Philosophy, Brooklyn College) Regarding Communists at Brooklyn College, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0216, Box-folder 11-RC429)
  - Fiorini, Remo (Secretary of Dante Aligheri Society): Includes Waiver of Immunity and Editorialized Summary of Interview with the Committee, Feb 1941-Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0331, Box-folder 11-RC430)
  - Giacobbe, Anita E. (Italian Teacher, Benjamin Franklin High School), Jul 1935, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0331, Box-folder 11-RC431)
  - Lieberman, Max (Chairman of French and Spanish, Townsend Harris High School), 1935-1938 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0354, Box-folder 11-RC432)
  - Milella, Nicholas J. (Teacher of French and Spanish, Townsend Harris High School), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0369, Box-folder 11-RC433)
  - Noverra, Anthony (Italian language student at Columbia University), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0373, Box-folder 11-RC434)
  - Pantaleoni, Geoffredo (Member and Officer of Dante Aligheri Society, Former Head of Italian Tourist Office): Includes Dies Committee Testimony, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0378, Box-folder 11-RC435)
  - Prezzolini, Giuseppi (associated with the Italian Tourist Office, Casa Italiana), Feb 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0450, Box-folder 11-RC436)
  - Ciancaglini-Gera, Mrs. Rena (Italian Teacher, Washington Irving High School), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0461, Box-folder 11-RC437)
  - Digest and Extracts of Salvemini Report, Oct 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0466, Box-folder 11-RC438)
  - Sammartino, Peter (French Teacher, Townsend Harris High School, C.C.N.Y.), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0475, Box-folder 11-RC439)
  - Sanfilippo, Anthony, Jul 1936 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0483, Box-folder 11-RC440)
  - Sereno, Dr. Renzo (Political Science, University of Chicago): Includes Dies Committee Testimony, HUAC, Nov 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0488, Box-folder 11-RC441)
  - Sorieri, Louis (Italian Teacher, New Utrecht High School), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0505, Box-folder 11-RC442)
  - Microfilm Error - No Folder, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0516, Box-folder 11-RC443)
  - Bureau of Extension Activities: Includes Lists and Reports on the Use of School Facilities by Communists and Anti-War Organizations, Mar 1935 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0517, Box-folder 11-RC444)
  - Board of Education Fascist File, Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0649, Box-folder 11-RC445)
  - Almanacco Della Associanzoni-Italo-Americane Edito Dalgeneroso: Pope Italian Newspaper Club Inc. New York, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0656, Box-folder 11-RC446)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano (Teacher, Harvard): Includes Newspaper and Periodical Clippings, Feb 1943-Nov 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0663, Box-folder 11-RC447)
  - Bonaschi, Dr. Alberto (Commissioner Board of Education): Includes Photostats of Newspapers and Periodicials, 1936-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 28-0759, Box-folder 11-RC448)
  - Survey of Il Progresso Italo-Americano: Includes Photostats of Articles, Sep 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0001, Box-folder 11-RC449)
  - Reading to be Checked from Library: List of Articles Relating to Italian Fascism, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0024, Box-folder 11-RC450)
  - Foreign Language Teachers: Includes Lists of Foreign Language Teachers in Junior High Schools and Modern and Classical Language Teachers in Senior High Schools, 1939-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0031, Box-folder 11-RC451)
  - Analysis of Il Grido Della Stirpe and Il Mondo, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0067, Box-folder 11-RC452)
  - Extension Activity Permits and Applications for Use of Rooms in Public School Buildings: Includes Correspondence on Possible Abuse of Policy by Italian Neighborhood Groups, 1937-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0081, Box-folder 11-RC453)
  - Italian Tourist Information Office: Includes List of Films Available for Exhibition, Sep 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0190, Box-folder 11-RC454)
  - Italian Chamber of Commerce: Includes List of Members in the United States, Dec 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0194, Box-folder 11-RC455)
  - Italian Fascism: Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews with Italian Americans, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0205, Box-folder 11-RC456)
  - Allegedly Pro-Fascist Organizations: Includes List of Pro-Fascist Organizations as Agreed to by Valenti (La Parola), Mr. Segre, Il Mondo, Venturi, Salvemini, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0214, Box-folder 11-RC457)
  - Reading List on Fascism, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0222, Box-folder 11-RC458)
  - Trips Abroad-Questions: Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews, Fifth Column Facts and Issues of La Parola, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0227, Box-folder 11-RC459)
  - Italian Line Records II: Includes Teachers, 1937-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0266, Box-folder 11-RC460)
  - Incorporation Papers of Italian-American Organizations, 1942-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0377, Box-folder 11-RC461)
  - New York Times Index: Includes List of Articles on Italian Fascism in the New York Times and Il Mondo, Jun 1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0392, Box-folder 11-RC462)
  - Trips to Europe (Italy and Germany): Includes Subpoena for Records of Italian Line and Correspondence Between the Italian Ambassador and the General Manager of Italian Line, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0549, Box-folder 11-RC463)
  - Italian American Society (re: DeVry Free Film Catalogue), 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0576, Box-folder 11-RC464)
  - Italian Textbooks in New York State: Includes Newspaper Clippings on Books Banned for Being Pro-Fascist, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0635, Box-folder 11-RC465)
  - Trips to Italy by Students (Winners of Prizes by Italian Government): Includes Correspondence from Rewards Committee and Trip Reports, 1934-1935 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0644, Box-folder 11-RC466)
  - Agents of Foreign Principals and Consular Officals List: Includes Correspondence Related to Lists, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0778, Box-folder 11-RC467)
  - Personnel Data: Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0844, Box-folder 11-RC468)
  - Foreign Language Teachers, High School, Junior High School, and CCNY Lists: Includes Correspondence between the Board of Education and Schools Regarding German Clubs, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0873, Box-folder 11-RC469)
  - List Taken From Almanac of Italo-American Associations and County Clerk's Office, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 29-0971, Box-folder 11-RC470)
  - Italian Magazines,and Newspapers: Includes Lists of Articles in Il Grido Della Stirpe, Fortune, Nation, Vittoriale, Carrocio, New York Times index, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 30-0001, Box-folder 11-RC471)
  - Italian Fascists, News Clippings: Includes Clippings from Il Grido Della Stirpe, La Parola, Corriere D'America, East Harlem News, Corriere Siciliano, 1941-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 30-0113, Box-folder 11-RC472)
  - List (from list of extension activities, confidential): Includes People and Newspaper Articles, Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 30-0209, Box-folder 11-RC473)
  - Italian Literature: Includes La Revista Commerciale, The New Republic, Counter Current, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 30-0232, Box-folder 11-RC474)
  - Italian Fascist Interviews: Includes News Clippings, Memoranda and Editorialized Summaries of Interviews, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 30-0281, Box-folder 11-RC475)
  - Italian Fascist Outline, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 30-0481, Box-folder 11-RC476)
  - New York City Coordinating Committee for Democratic Action Attack on United States Regarding Fascist Activities: Includes Memorandum from Coordinating Committee Charging Rapp-Coudert with not Following Leads on Fascist Cases, 1938-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 30-0522, Box-folder 11-RC477)
  - Tom Meehan Report on Fascism (A Major Source of Info For the Committee): Includes Committee Index and Issues of Il Mondo, 1935-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 31-0001, Box-folder 12-RC478)
  - Confidential Material on Italian Fascism; Report by Salvemini on "Italian Fascism in New York City" (Includes Digest and Extracts of Report), 1942-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0001, Box-folder 12-RC479)
  - Grido (Il Grido Della Stirpe) Photostats, 1936-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0500, Box-folder 12-RC480)
  - American Committee for the German Relief Fund Inc.: Includes Library of Congress List of References to Nazi Fifth Column Activities, 1941-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0598, Box-folder 12-RC481)
  - Camp Nordland-Christian Front (Andover, New Jersey): Includes List of Names and Addresses from Camp Nordland, List of Interviewees re: Fascism, Naziism, May 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0633, Box-folder 12-RC482)
  - Martens, Herman - Vorpahl, Karl - Holwedel, Fred - Hohenstein, "Kingfish" - Shlottenbeck, Walter (members of the German Bund and students at William Cullen Bryant High School interviewed by the committee), Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0681, Box-folder 12-RC483)
  - Material from Dick Rollins: Includes Waivers of Immunity and Photographs of German Bund Marches, May 1941-Sep 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0692, Box-folder 12-RC484)
  - Herman Notes and Memos of Special Non-Nazi Jobs: Includes Memoranda on Filing of Statements of Expenditure for the Communist Party and Attempts to Subpoena Robert Miller (Secretary CPUSA), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0701, Box-folder 12-RC485)
  - Class, Rheingold G. (Former Student at Stuyvesant High Schoool, Member of Deutches Jugend in Amerika, Refused to Testify): Includes Hearing and Contempt Proceedings, Issues of Homemade Magazine Junges Volk, 1938-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 32-0750, Box-folder 12-RC486)
  - Hallberg, Dr. Charles W. (Brooklyn College, Extension Division): Includes Correspondence Denouncing Hallberg and Editorialized Summaries of Interviews with Hallberg's Former Students, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0001, Box-folder 12-RC489)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee: Includes Waivers of Immunity and Issues of Der Trumpeter a Publication of the William Cullen Bryant High School (Long Island City) German Club, 1937-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0025, Box-folder 12-RC490)
  - Nazi Memoranda N Files: Includes Editorialized Summaries of Interviews with Students, May 1943-Jun 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0119, Box-folder 12-RC491)
  - North German-Lloyd-Hamburg-American Lines: Includes List of Individuals Sailing on Steamships to Germany, Feb 1941-Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0127, Box-folder 12-RC492)
  - German-Nazi: Includes Resolution Adopted by American Association of Teachers of German, Open Letter from the Association Denouncing Hitler and Correspondence between the Association and the Rapp-Coudert Committee, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0183, Box-folder 12-RC493)
  - Leinhard Bergel (Queens College, German): Includes Correspondence between Leinhard Bergel and the Rapp-Coudert Committee on the Investigation and Subsequent Dissappearance of his Former Supervisor Fredrich J Hauptmann (later part of the Nazi Puppet Regime in Slovakia), Mar 1941-Apr 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0223, Box-folder 12-RC494)
  - Jersey Bund Raid at Camp Nordland in Andover, New Jersey: Includes News Clippings on FBI Raid and List of Names, May 1941-Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0238, Box-folder 12-RC495)
  - McCann, Alice (Winthrop Jr. High School, Brooklyn): Includes Correspondence Denouncing McCann, 1942-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0261, Box-folder 12-RC496)
  - Microfilm Error: No Folder (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0273, Box-folder 12-RC497)
  - Nazi Clippings: Includes The Anti-Nazi Bulletin, The New York Post, The New York Daily News, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0274, Box-folder 12-RC498)
  - Kaehny, Siegfried (Member German-American Vocational League), 1938-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0408, Box-folder 12-RC499)
  - Muller, Otto (Assistant Professor French and Romance Language, CCNY): Includes Correspondence Denouncing Muller as a Nazi, 1942-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0428, Box-folder 13-RC500)
  - Von Bradisch, Joseph A. (Assistant Professor of German, CCNY): Includes Correspondence in German between Von Bradisch and a Nazi Official, Memorandum on Alleged Nazi Sympathies, 1941-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0434, Box-folder 13-RC501)
  - Nazi Angle: Includes Correspondence Regarding Nazism Addressed to Paul Windels upon Assuming the Office of Counsel for Rapp Coudert-Committee, 1934-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0443, Box-folder 13-RC502)
  - Senate Bill, NYS #1480 "To Amend the Education Law" Sponsored by Senator Coudert, Mar 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0498, Box-folder 13-RC503)
  - Balet, Leonard F. (Art History Professor, Brooklyn College) and Chermayoff, Serge Ivan (Chairman, Department of Art and Drafting, Brooklyn College): Includes Correspondence, Memoranda, and News Clippings Regarding Reappointment Controversies of Leonard Balet and Loris A. Withers (Professor, Brooklyn College), 1941-1944 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 33-0600, Box-folder 13-RC504)